Dhaker Sghaier

Monastir, Tunisia (T) +216 95275689 (E) dhakersg@gmail.com



PROFILE

As a DevOps enthusiast, I have hands-on experience in the AWS Cloud, configuration management via Ansible, and building CI/CD pipelines with Jenkins. My commitment to mastering the principles and tools of DevOps stimulates me to contribute meaningfully to collaborative teams as I continue to develop my skills.

EXPERIENCE

SW Consulting - Full-time DevOps **DevOps & Cloud Engineer**

10/2023 - Present

- Dockerize and Adapt containerization's concept of all existing projects.
- Setting up a robust infrastructure for each project using AWS CLI and Terraform, guaranteeing simplified cloud resources's management.
- Deploy Jenkins CI/CD pipelines for microservices architecture projects.
- Automatic backup management.
- Deploy AWS Lambda functions for cost optimisation.
- Setup monitoring Dashboard using Prometheus and Grafana.

TOOLS: Terraform, Jenkins, Bash, Docker, AWS RDS EC2 CloudWatch Lambda S3, Prometheus et Grafana.

SW Consulting - Intenship

07/2023 - 09/2023

DevOps & Cloud

- Set up the cloud infrastructure with Terraform for a single project.
- Automated system configurations using custom Ansible playbooks.
- Used Docker for containerisation, simplifying application deployment.
- Created Jenkins CI/CD pipeline for code deployment.

TOOLS: Terraform, Jenkins, Ansible, Docker, AWS RDS EC2

ADN Expertise - End Of Study Internship

02/2023 - 06/2023

Cloud & DevOps

Completed two projects with AWS, demonstrated my expertise in Cloud architecture design, AWS services and data analysis. These projects included:

- implementation of the AWS Organization service for Organizational requirement.
- designed Cloud architecture for predicting student results, in line with organisational objectives.

TOOLS: AWS Services, JSON, Terraform

SOTUPA - Internship

06/2022 - 08/2022

Networking

Ensuring the stable operation of computer networks. This includes planning, installing, configuring, maintaining and optimising all network hardware, software and communication links.

TOOLS: Linux, Cisco CLI, NAC, NMS, Firewall

REALISED PROJECTS –

Implemention of Microservices Architecture with Spring Boot, Eureka, API Gateway and Config-Server:

- Set-up Spring Cloud Netflix Eureka for the dynamic Service discovery and registration of services instances.
- Configure API Gateway with Spring Cloud Gateway for centralised entry points management.

 Deploye Config Server with Spring Cloud Config for centralised and dynamic management of microservices configuration.

TOOLS: Netflix SpringBoot Stack, Docker, EC2

Azure Customer Environment Management:

- Develop multi-tenant system with automated database provisioning in Azure.
- Provision databases in Azure Flexible MySQL Server Using Azure CLI.
- Develop a script triggered by a webhook as soon as a user purchases a subscription, automating the process of creating an environment for the new customer.
- · Implement security mesurments ensuring data isolation between different environments.

TOOLS: Azure CLI, Azure MySQL Flexible Server, Github Actions

Development of Automated EC2 Instance Management System for Cost Optimisation on AWS:

Implementation of an automated system using AWS Lambda and Amazon EventBridge to stop and start EC2 instances with "DEV" Tags after working hours and at weekends, ensuring continuous optimisation of costs while maintaining the availability of resources needed for development.

TOOLS

- · Bash, Python
- Linux, Windows shell
- · AWS cloud (AWS CLI)
- Spring Cloud (Eureka API Gateway)
- MySQL

- Docker (compose /Swarm)
- Terraform
- Ansible
- · Jenkins, Github Actions
- Azure CLI
- Prometheus, Grafana

CERTIFICATIONS —

- CCNA1: Configure, maintain and troubleshoot network equipment.
- CCNA2: Initial router configuration, Cisco IOS software management, TCP/IP routing protocol configuration..
- AWS Academy Cloud Foundations.
- Fundamentals of Accelerated Data Science from NVIDIA.

EDUCATION

Computer Science Engineering Present (Adapted course)

Ecole Pluridisciplinaire International of Sousse EPI

Licence in Telecommunications 2020-2023

High Institut of Information and Communication Technologies Hammem Sousse

Baccalauréat Technique 2020

High School Sayada, Monastir

ADDITIONAL ACTIVITIES

Nuit de L'info Challenge: 2nd place worldwide

Pitch Challenge December 2022

Media Manager ATAST Club ISITCOM

Community Manager 2021-2022 Content Director

B-TECH COMPETITION

2nd place in the competition

2021 Best club coach prize

Scouts

2008-2018 Team Leader

Wrestling 2008-2017

One time Tunisia champion